STAVROS TSOGKAS

6 King's College Rd., Toronto, Ontario, Canada http://www.cs.toronto.edu/~tsogkas email: tsogkas@cs.toronto.edu

Research Interests

My research interests are in the broad areas of computer vision and machine learning, with a focus on deep learning. I am particularly interested in the use of mid-level representations to bridge the gap between bottom-up and top-down processing and solve problems such as object detection, segmentation and grouping. I have devoted a large part of my research on recovering such representations, medial axes and object parts in particular, in natural and medical images.

Education

CentraleSupélec

Jan. 2016

Ph.D. in Mathematics and Computer Science

Thesis: Mid-level Representations for Modeling Objects

Advisor: Iasonas Kokkinos

National Technical University of Athens

Sep. 2011

Diploma in Electrical and Computer Engineering

Thesis: Learning-Based Symmetry Detection in Natural Images

Advisors: Petros Maragos, Iasonas Kokkinos

Peer-reviewed Conference Publications

- AMAT: Medial Axis Transform for Natural Images, ICCV 2017
 S. Tsogkas, S. Dickinson
- Prior-based Coregistration and Cosegmentation, MICCAI 2016
 M. Shakeri*, E. Ferrante*, S. Tsogkas, S. Lippe, S. Kadoury, I. Kokkinos, N. Paragios (* denotes equal contribution)
- Subcortical Brain Structure Segmentation Using FCNNs, ISBI 2016 (oral)
 S. Tsogkas*, M. Shakeri*, E. Ferrante, S. Lippe, S. Kadoury, N. Paragios, I. Kokkinos (* denotes equal contribution)
- Accurate Human-Limb Segmentation in RGB-D images for Intelligent Mobility Assistance Robots
 - ICCV 2015 3^{rd} Workshop on Assistive Computer Vision and Robotics S. Chandra, **S. Tsogkas**, I. Kokkinos
- Deformable Part Models with CNN Features,
 ECCV 2014 Parts and Attributes workshop
 P.-A. Savalle, S. Tsogkas, G. Papandreou and I. Kokkinos
- Superpixel-grounded Deformable Part Models, CVPR 2014
 E. Trulls, S. Tsogkas, I. Kokkinos, A. Sanfeliu, F.Moreno
- Understanding Objects in Detail with Fine-grained Attributes, CVPR 2014
 A. Vedaldi, S. Mahendran, S. Tsogkas, S. Maji, B. Girshick, J. Kannala, E. Rahtu, I. Kokkinos, M. B. Blaschko, D. Weiss, B. Taskar, K. Simonyan, N. Saphra, S. Mohamed
- Learning-Based Symmetry Detection in Natural Images, ECCV 2012
 S. Tsogkas, I. Kokkinos

Reports

• ICCV 2017 Challenge: Detecting Symmetry in the Wild (editorial), Detecting symmetry in the wild workshop, ICCV 2017 Chris Funk*, Seungkyu Lee*, Martin R. Oswald*, Stavros Tsogkas*, Wei Shen, Andrea Cohen, Sven Dickinson, Yanxi Liu (* denotes equal contribution)

 Deep Learning for Semantic Part Segmentation with High-Level Guidance, $arXiv\ report$

S. Tsogkas, I. Kokkinos, G. Papandreou, A. Vedaldi

Research Experience

Samsung Research America

Sep. 2018 - present

Research Scientist, Samsung AI Center Toronto

Vector Institute for Artificial Intelligence

Jan. 2018 - present

Affiliate postdoctoral fellow

University of Toronto

Oct. 2016 - Sep. 2018

Postdoctoral fellow, Computer Science Department

Supervisor: Sven Dickinson

CentraleSupélec

Jan. 2016 - Aug. 2016

Research engineer, CVN lab Supervisor: Nikos Paragios

Convolutional neural networks for semantic segmentation of organs in computed tomography scans.

Oxford University (Visual Geometry Group)

Aug.-Nov. 2014

Research intern

Supervisor: Andrea Vedaldi.

Combined convolutional neural networks and restricted boltzmann machines for semantic segmentation of object parts.

Teaching Experience

Teaching assistant (CentraleSupélec)

2011-2015

- Signal Processing (undegrad course).
- Computer Vision (undegrad course).
- Machine Learning for Computer Vision (MVA master course)

Invited lecturer (CentraleSupélec/ESSEC)

2016

MSc in Data Science and Business Analytics Seminar on deep learning theory and tools.

Professional Activities

Reviewer, IEEE TPAMI, IJCV, CVIU, IMAVIS, IEEE ICCV, IEEE CVPR, ECCV, ICVGIP, BMVC, Morgan & Claypool Synthesis lectures on Computer Vision

Co-organizer of the "Detecting Symmetry in the Wild" workshop,

in conjunction with ICCV 2017, Venice, Italy.

Treasurer, IEEE NTUA Student Branch2010-2011Chairman, IEEE NTUA Student Branch2011-2012Student member IEEE2012-2015

Programming Skills

MATLAB, Python, Lua, C++, Latex, Caffe, MatConvNet, Torch.

Distinctions

Outstanding reviewer award (ECCV 2016)

Citizenship Greek

Languages English (fluent), French (proficient), Greek (native).